(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
- My name is Catherine and today we have
a very dramatic intermediate
level lesson for you.
- That's right, today
we're gonna take a look
at how a court works, for
example, in the United States.
So you see that in movies and TV shows
a lot, you know, the judge and all that.
- That's right, many of you
have seen the movie The Firm
or a 12 Angry Man, these are classics
in, you know, courtroom dramas, we say.
So today we're in a
courtroom and there are many
characters who are trying
to determine if this person
is innocent or guilty.
So let's take a lesson and
find out what's going on.
(upbeat music)
- Your honor, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
my client, Robert Malone, has been
accused of a crime he did not commit.
The prosecution has accused
my client of being a pickpocket.
I know we have heard the
testimony of many people here today.
People who claim the defendant,
my client stole their wallets.
I feel sorry for these
victims, I really do.
But my client is innocent.
Let's look at the facts.
Number one, these so-called witnesses
did not actually see the
defendant steal anything.
Number two, when the police stopped him,
he did not have any of the stolen wallets.
There is no evidence.
Therefore, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
I ask you to think carefully
before giving your verdict.
Look at the facts, look at the evidence.
My client is innocent.
- Ladies and gentlemen of the
jury, have you reached a verdict?
- Yes, your honor.
A verdict is not guilty.
(cheering)
- Thank you so much, you were great.
- Thank you for all your hard work.
- You're welcome, Robert.
I knew you were innocent,
so my job was easy.
Take care of yourself, okay?
- Thanks once again.
- Hey, where's my wallet?
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back, so
you've probably heard a lot of
technical words that
are specifically related
to the courtroom, to
lawyers, and the laws.
So why don't we take a look at some
of those now in language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
The first language takeaway we're
looking at today is all about people.
So people you will find in a courtroom.
Who's the first person on our list, Marco?
- So the top person would
be the judge, the judge.
Now you didn't really see this
word judge in the dialogue, right?
- You did hear, though,
the phrase, your honor.
- Your honor.
- So your honor.
- So that's how you talk to a judge.
You always add your
honor before it or something.
- That's right, so
you know we say, Mr.
President, when we're
talking to Barack Obama.
But if we're talking to a judge, he's
a special person in American society.
So we call him or her, your honor.
- Your honor, okay.
- All right, your honor, the judge.
That's our first person.
- Okay, who else do we have?
- So we have the judge
and now we have a group
of 12 people who will ultimately
decide if the person is guilty or not.
- That's right, so these people are normal.
They come from all
different parts of society
and they will decide what
to do with this person.
Is he guilty or is she innocent?
This group is called the jury.
- Okay, so the jury is a
group of normal citizens
who will listen to
both sides of the story
and will then decide if the person committed
the crime or didn't commit the crime.
- That's right, a jury.
And the big question is who's fighting?
We have two sides, someone who is upset
and someone who is defending themselves.
The person who is upset,
this is the prosecution.
- Okay, so the
prosecution has a group of
lawyers that are called
the prosecutors, right?
- That's right.
- And they're trying to prove that
that person committed the crime.
- For example, I say that
Marco burned down my house.
I go to court, I say I am the prosecution.
I want him to pay me for my house.
So I'm the prosecution.
- Okay, so you're trying to not only prove
that I committed the
crime, but also trying
to get me to pay for
the damage that I caused.
- Exactly, so in this case,
the prosecution says,
this man stole my
wallet, he's a big pocket.
And who's the pickpocket
or maybe the pickpocket?
Who's the other side of this?
- The defendant.
- Defend, defendant,
think about the word here.
To defend is to stand up for
yourself, to protect yourself.
- Right.
- So the defendant says,
listen, no, that's not true.
I am not a pickpocket.
- I didn't do that.
- So we have the prosecution
and the defense, okay?
And the person who might be guilty,
the person who did the thing or didn't
do the thing is called the defendant.
- Okay, so in your example again,
about the crime that maybe I
burnt your house down or I didn't,
I would be the defendant and my
lawyers would constitute my defense.
- Yeah, they are your defense, okay?
- Okay, so very technical words,
but the important thing to
remember here is defendant.
- All right, good.
So now we have one key
element that is also a person
we have the witness.
- Right, so the basic idea like
you said is we have to tell a story.
My story is that you burned down my
house and you say, no, I didn't, prove it.
I say, I can't, someone
saw you with a lighter.
- Okay.
- And so this person is my witness.
That means that he or
she saw what happened.
So someone who sees a
crime is a witness to that crime.
- Okay, very good.
So a lot of people are in the
courtroom, a lot of things are happening.
So I think we should
listen to the dialogue again
and we'll be back to look at some more
words on language takeaway part two.
- Your honor, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
my client Robert Malone has been
accused of a crime he did not commit.
The prosecution has accused
my client of being a pickpocket.
I know we have heard the
testimony of many people here today.
People who claim the defendant,
my client stole their wallets.
I feel sorry for these
victims, I really do.
But my client is innocent.
Let's look at the facts.
Number one, these so called witnesses
did not actually see the
defendant steal anything.
Number two, when the police stopped him,
he did not have any of the stolen wallets.
There is no evidence.
Therefore, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
I ask you to think carefully
before giving your verdict.
Look at the facts, look at the evidence.
My client is innocent.
- Ladies and gentlemen of the
jury, have you reached a verdict?
- Yes, your honor,
our verdict is not guilty.
- Thank you so much, you were great.
Thank you for all your hard work.
You're welcome Robert, I knew
your innocent so my job was easy.
Take care of yourself, okay?
- Thanks once again.
- Hey, where's my wallet?
- I love it when we do this.
So many words, so much
language to take away.
- That's right.
So now we're going to take a look at
the second part of language to take away
where we have another set of four
words that we wanna take a look at.
- Language takeaway.
All right, the first is actually two words.
We have two opposites, okay?
See you said earlier, the
jury has to make a decision.
- Mm-hmm.
- The jury has to decide, is the
defendant innocent or guilty?
- Okay.
- Okay, these are two
important adjectives, innocent.
What does this mean?
- So if he is innocent, that
means he did not commit
the crime, he is not
responsible for what happened.
He did not steal the wallets.
- Okay, so we often say
babies are so innocent.
- Right.
- They can't do anything.
- They don't do anything wrong.
- Right.
- So guilty would be the opposite.
- That's right.
- So usually when
someone is guilty, they're
sad, they feel bad, you
want them to pay you.
- And they go to jail.
- Yeah, in bad situations, they go to jail.
If you burn down my house, of
course you're gonna go to jail.
- Right.
- All right, so guilty means you
did a crime, you did a bad thing.
- So we talked about the
prosecution and the defense
of the defendant and what
happens is they also present
some key elements that will prove
if the person is innocent or guilty.
And those elements are called evidence.
- That's right, so back to this idea,
we tell a story, maybe a
witness can help us tell our story,
but as you say, evidence
is stuff, it's things.
So in the case of the house, I could say,
you have matches and
you smell like smoke and oil.
This is evidence for me to
use to show that you are guilty.
- Right.
- So in this case, do we have any evidence?
There is no evidence,
says the defendant, right.
- All right, so evidence is proof.
- It's proof.
- It's a physical proof.
- Yeah, and most of the
times when you see movies
or TV shows, they will find,
I don't know, like maybe
a fingerprints, that's evidence,
or somebody's glasses.
- A cell phone. - Exactly.
- All right, so evidence, this is very
important when you wanna build a case.
Finally, at the end of the
trial, we have a verdict.
Now, what is a verdict?
- So a verdict is a final
decision or a conclusion
in which the jury says, yeah, the person is
guilty or he's not guilty, he's innocent.
So we use this word
usually to reach a verdict.
The jury reaches a verdict.
- Now, it's interesting why we say to reach,
because a jury is not just one person.
A jury is many people.
And so these people
have to decide together,
they have to argue, they have to make
a conclusion that everyone agrees on.
And this is to reach
a conclusion, to reach
a verdict, because they
have to travel there.
They have to go together and figure it out.
- Right, that's very, very important.
So the jury reaches a verdict.
- And we did have one other
phrase, it's very interesting.
It doesn't quite fit with the other ones.
We heard this phrase from the defendant.
The lawyer says, so these so-called
witnesses didn't actually see anything.
What is so called?
- So he's being sarcastic
when he uses this phrase.
So called, right?
That's why his, even his tone
changes these so-called witnesses.
So it's a way of expressing sarcasm.
He's saying they say they are witnesses,
but they're not really, because
they didn't see anything.
- Right, so so-called means you say
that they are, but they're not really.
- Right.
- I could also say, you're so-called lawyer
thinks he can help you, but he can't.
- Right.
- That means, I don't think
your lawyer is very good.
I don't think he's a real lawyer.
- Right, or sometimes people say, my
so-called friends stood me up last night.
- Oh, so it's not really a friend.
- It's not really a friend, exactly.
- So called, all right,
that's another good one.
Let's listen to this
dialogue one more time.
Really think about some of the words you
heard today and we'll be back in a moment.
(upbeat music)
- Your honor, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
my client, Robert Malone, has been
accused of a crime he did not commit.
The prosecution has accused
my client of being a pickpocket.
I know we have heard the
testimony of many people here today.
People who claim the defendant,
my client, stole their wallets.
I feel sorry for these victims.
I really do, but my client is innocent.
Let's look at the facts.
Number one, these so-called witnesses
did not actually see the
defendant steal anything.
Number two, when the police stopped him,
he did not have any of the stolen wallets.
There is no evidence.
Therefore, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
I ask you to think carefully
before giving your verdict.
Look at the facts, look at the evidence.
My client is innocent.
- Ladies and gentlemen of the
jury, have you reached a verdict?
Yes, your honor, our verdict is not guilty.
- Thank you so much, you were great.
Thank you for all your hard work.
- You're welcome, Robert.
I knew you were innocent,
so my job was easy.
Take care of yourself, okay?
- Thanks once again.
- Hey, where's my wallet?
- All right, we're back.
So now a very interesting situation
with the courtroom dramas, and
I've heard that all the people in the jury
have to agree in order for
them to reach a verdict, right?
So if one of them is not convinced
that the person is, for example, guilty,
then they have to keep on
deliberating, that's the word, right?
- That's right, so basically
the jury is always alone
in a room, maybe they have a guard, but
they're not supposed to talk to journalists
or friends of the defendant or anyone,
because their decision is supposed to be pure.
So they talk, and sometimes
it takes 10 minutes.
Everyone agrees, this person is
guilty, or if this person is innocent,
but sometimes they don't
agree, and it can be one day.
Two days, a week, two weeks, a
month trying to decide what to do.
I remember in the OJ
Simpson case, the jury took a
long time to figure out
what they were going to do.
- And now we said that
the jury are common citizens,
they're normal people, so
what happens in their jobs?
Like if they can't go to work
because they're doing this.
- Well in America,
this job is called jury
duty, and so someone
will send you a letter,
and they say listen, you
need to come do jury duty,
and you help be a part of the jury,
and your job, they can't make you come,
because this is a service
for the government.
- So it's above everything else.
- It's above, you get your normal pay,
there's no problem, you just don't work.
- Okay, so they can't
fire you if you're in jury
duty for like five days
or a month or whatever.
- No, they can't, that's illegal.
- Wow, that's really interesting.
But a lot of people I've heard don't
like to go to jury duty for some reason.
It's, is it?
- No, it's probably very boring, I've never
done it, but it's probably very boring.
- I would imagine so.
All right, well that's a
very interesting topic,
I'm sure in your countries,
laws are handled differently,
maybe you don't have a
courtroom, maybe you have like
an England people wear
wigs and black robes,
so let us know how it
works in your countries,
we'll see everyone at
our website, EnglishPot.
com, and of course, if
you have any questions
or comments, you can
leave those there as well.
- See you on the website and happy studies.
- Bye everyone.
(upbeat music)